<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on A Hugo website</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on A Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of a Visual Aid</title>
      <link>/2019/05/06/the-importance-of-a-visual-aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/06/the-importance-of-a-visual-aid/</guid>
      <description>Visualations are the easiest way to get a point across or to tell a story. One’s visual can make or break a presentation, so its safe to say that you shouldn’t take them lightly. Its important to take in to acount what your visiaul is telling the world and whether its telling the world the correct thing.
plot3&amp;lt;-ggplot(facebook, aes(party))+ geom_bar()+ ggtitle(&amp;quot;Politcal Party&amp;quot;)plot2&amp;lt;-ggplot(facebook, aes(party, fill= party))+ geom_bar()+ ggtitle(&amp;quot;Politcal Party&amp;quot;)+ scale_fill_manual(&amp;quot;legend&amp;quot;, values = c(&amp;quot;Democratic Party&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;blue&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Republican Party&amp;quot; = &amp;quot;red&amp;quot;)) + theme(legend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Models</title>
      <link>/2019/04/29/basic-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/29/basic-models/</guid>
      <description>\[LocalTopic=\beta_o+ \beta_1OpposeAny \]
model&amp;lt;- lm(local_topic~oppose_any, data= facebook)pander::pander(summary(model))EstimateStd. Errort valuePr(&amp;gt;|t|)(Intercept)0.55250.005098108.40oppose_any-0.70870.02753-25.744.929e-114Fitting linear model: local_topic ~ oppose_anyObservationsResidual Std. Error\(R^2\)Adjusted \(R^2\)10680.11540.38330.3828For every one unit increase of the proportion of posts that oppose rival political parties/beliefs, the proportion of posts that are about their state or district decrease by .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intermediate Anaylsis</title>
      <link>/2019/04/29/intermediate-anaylsis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/29/intermediate-anaylsis/</guid>
      <description>K-Fold Cross-ValidationThe k-fold method involves randomly dividing the set of observations into k groups or folds of approximately equal sizes. The process involves all but one using those to train your data and then using that one to test the efficiency of your model. After averaging the mean standard error from each of the k tests we can tell how well our model is predicting. Lower the number indicating a better model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethics of Data Science</title>
      <link>/2019/04/25/ethics-of-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/25/ethics-of-data-science/</guid>
      <description>After perusing through the data is beautiful thread the first thing that caught my eye were all the stunning graphs that people created. For example i came across a visual of united states that showed where each state placed based on per capita per sales of different alcoholic beverages. I was shocked to see that new Hampshire was the top five if nor first place for all of them. I would assume though they raked the states by proportions not by just sheer amount.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The begining of a Data Sceince Project</title>
      <link>/2019/04/25/the-begining-of-a-data-sceince-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/25/the-begining-of-a-data-sceince-project/</guid>
      <description>DataThe data set comes from the Pew research center. It explores 1068 different members of congress from the 114th and 115th congress and their Facebook post trends. The data set was already clean. \
Variables\(\textbf{Party}\): Used to differentiate between a Democrat or a Republican.\(\textbf{Oppose any}\): The proportion of posts in which each member opposed Barack Obama, Hillary Clinton, or Democrats and/or liberals (if the member is a Republican) or the proportion of posts in which each member opposed Donald Trump or Republicans and/or conservatives (if the member is a Democrat), in each congress.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>